<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE faq SYSTEM "faq.dtd">
<faq>
 <copyright>2007 Gary Benson</copyright>
 <!-- XXX this should probably be page-by-page -->
 <entries>
  <entry id="whatIsShiatsu" top="yes">
   <question>
     What is shiatsu?
   </question>
   <answer>
    <p>
     Shiatsu is a hands-on therapy that combines modern anatomy and
     physiology with traditional Chinese medicine.
    </p>
    <p>
     In shiatsu mind, body and spirit are not separate, but viewed as
     different aspects of an underlying whole.  Pain and disease are
     seen as imbalances in the flow of energy through this whole.  By
     gently stretching and moving the body, shiatsu aims to restore
     the flow of this energy to its natural state of balance and
     harmony.
    </p>
    <p>
     Treating the person as a whole makes shiatsu relevant to many
     conditions, be they physical, emotional or spiritual in nature.
     Problems of the body are often reflections of problems of the
     mind or of the heart, and working the body can help to initiate a
     deeper healing.
    </p>
    <p>
     Shiatsu is performed fully clothed, with the receiver lying on a
     futon.  A typical session lasts about an hour<!-- and costs
     &price; -->.
    </p>
   </answer>
   <links>
    <link question="howShiatsuCanHelp"/>
    <link question="whatWillHappen"/>
   </links>
  </entry>
  <entry id="howShiatsuCanHelp" top="yes">
   <question>
    How can shiatsu help me?
   </question>
   <answer>
    <p>
     Shiatsu is a form of healing, but that doesn't mean you need to
     be ill to benefit from it.  Many people have shiatsu as part of
     their regime to maintain good health: a small amount of regular
     attention helps prevent little things turning into bigger
     problems.  Others have shiatsu as a tonic, to relax and
     revitalise themselves.  Everyday life can take it out of you,
     and shiatsu is an excellent way to put something back.
    </p>
   </answer>
   <links>
    <link question="whatWillHappen"/>
    <link question="whatToWear"/>
   </links>
  </entry>
  <entry id="whatToWear" top="yes">
   <question>
    What should I wear for my shiatsu?
   </question>
   <answer>
    <p>
     Shiatsu is performed fully clothed, so please bring or wear
     loose, warm, comfortable clothing.  A sweatshirt and tracksuit
     trousers would be ideal.  Long sleeves and socks are recommended
     as your temperature may drop during the treatment.  Jeans are not
     ideal, and please don't wear a skirt or a dress.  You may change
     here if you like.
    </p>
   </answer>
   <links>
    <link question="whatWillHappen"/>
    <link question="howWillIFeelAfter"/>
   </links>
  </entry>
  <entry id="whatWillHappen" top="yes">
   <question>
    What will happen during my shiatsu session?
   </question>
   <answer>
    <p>
     Your shiatsu session will start with a consultation.  I'll ask a
     few questions about your health: how you are feeling, whether you
     have any areas of tension or soreness, and if you have any
     specific medical conditions.  This is basically where I get to
     find out what you would like from your shiatsu.  We'll discuss
     what will happen in your treatment, and I'll answer any questions
     you may have.
    </p>
    <p>
     Then comes the treatment itself.  This lasts 40-45 minutes.
     Afterwards there will be a little time to talk, and I may show
     you a stretch or two you can try yourself if I found any
     particular areas of stiffness.
    </p>
   </answer>
   <links>
    <link question="howWillIFeelAfter"/>
    <link question="whatToWear"/>
   </links>
  </entry>
  <entry id="howWillIFeelAfter" top="yes">
   <question>
    How will I feel after my shiatsu?
   </question>
   <answer>
    <p>
     For most people the most obvious result of their shiatsu is a
     deep feeling of relaxation and calm.  Some people find it leaves
     them feeling sleepy; others report feeling energised and
     invigorated.  One interpretation of shiatsu is that it gently
     reminds your body of what it needs, so if you need sleep then
     you'll feel sleepy and if you need to go out and do something
     then you'll feel like going out and doing something.  Every
     single person and every single treatment is different, and the
     full effects may take some time to unfold.
    </p>
   </answer>
   <links>
    <link question="whatToWear"/>
   </links>
  </entry>
 </entries>
</faq>
<!--
  Local Variables:
  mode: html
  End:
  -->
